# Randy Burgess

Kansas City, 773-551-6808, wrburgess@wrburgess.com

I have 22+ years of experience as a technology leader, software engineer, and instructor/mentor.

I am seeking a position that needs technical leadership and software development experience. I can build and nurture engineering teams, solve business problems with technical solutions, and architect processes at every level to ensure application quality. I am capable of splitting my time between managerial and hands-on development duties when necessary.

I interface well with executives, non-technical staff, clients, users, and engineers, alike. In every business I've been a part of, it's the people, not the technology or tools, that have mattered the most for team and product success.

#### Skills

**Management**: Application development, small business technology leadership, hiring, mentoring, budgeting, disaster recovery, compliance, networking, infrastructure, databases, backup planning, continuous integration, automated testing, Agile and Kanban project management

**Technologies**: Ruby on Rails, React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, Golang, Python, RabbitMQ, React Native, Vue.js, Typescript, D3.js, Ruby, MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase RTDB, Firebase Firestore, Drupal, WordPress, REST API, Git, Heroku, Elasticsearch, Sidekiq, Redis, SendGrid, Twilio, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, TDD, Jest, RSpec, Cypress, HTML, CSS, Jira, Trello, Codeship, Continuous Integration/Deployment, SOA

# **Experience**

#### Shipwell – Senior Engineering Manager (Remote, Oct 2020 – present)

- Inherited management of two teams building microservices for internal and external APIs
- Managed squad of fully remote engineers and contractors, both domestic and offshore
- Python, RabbitMQ, AWS, MVC, microservices, integrations, Restful APIs, hiring, onboarding, Jira, project management, EDI, Supply Chain and Logistics

#### Hireology – Engineering Manager (Remote, Jun 2019 – Oct 2020)

- Inherited management of team building Service Oriented Architecture applications
- Rapidly learned Golang, RabbitMQ for hands-on work
- Go, RabbitMQ, Ruby on Rails, Node, React, Jest, Cypress, RSpec, PostgreSQL, Twilio, SendGrid, Postman, API Integration, Codeship, GitHub, Jira, Recruiting Technologies

## All Aboard Apps - Consultant (Remote, Jan 2016 – Jun 2019)

- Built new Ruby on Rails, D3 reports and charting system on Heroku and AWS for client
- Provided long-term maintenance and feature additions for Ruby on Rails application
- Ruby on Rails, Node, React, React Native, Vue, Jest, Cypress, RSpec, PostgreSQL,
  Firebase, Codeship, CircleCi, GitHub, Trello, Ecommerce, Media Property Management

## Northwestern University - Lead Instructor (Onsite, Jan 2017 - Jul 2017)

- Teaching 28 students full stack web development skills over a six-month course
- Curriculum includes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, MySQL, React, APIs

## Innovations for Learning - CTO & Engineer (Remote, Apr 2014 - Dec 2015)

- Recommended critical fixes to stabilize overwhelmed legacy app
- Recruited new team to rebuild Ruby on Rails application and REST API
- Ruby on Rails, React.js, PhoneGap, PostgreSQL, AWS, Education Technology

## DevMynd Software - Full Stack Engineer (Onsite, Jul 2012 - Apr 2014)

- Most projects utilized Ruby on Rails, Ember.js, Heroku, and AWS technologies
- Lead Developer on video upload and distribution application hosted on AWS
- Built custom asset order and payment system using Ruby on Rails and Foxycart
- Used TDD with Ruby on Rails with RSpec extensively, Ecommerce

## Vibes Media - Application Developer (Onsite, Nov 2011 - Jun 2012)

- Moved into Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, and RESTful API development
- Installed responsive designs into HTML5 and CSS3 website interfaces
- Deployed campaigns with SMS, Facebook, and Twitter-based interactions
- Mentored co-workers to move careers towards application development

## JBRB - Contractor/Developer (Remote, Feb 2011 - Nov 2011)

- Websites, CMS, and custom application development
- Project management and product development

## Horizon Cash Management - VP of Tech (Onsite, Apr 2001 - Jan 2011)

- Managed all technology decisions, budget direction, and purchasing
- Managed two assistants, multiple vendors, and all technology hiring and training
- Utilized Windows Server, SQL Server, Access, ASP.NET, Bloomberg

#### Insider Sports Media - Lead Developer (Remote, 2009 - 2011)

- Lead developer for an online sports publishing company
- Utilizing ASP.NET, SQL Server, ¡Query, AJAX, JavaScript, CSS, & HTML

## Taproot Foundation - Volunteer Developer (Remote, 2008 - 2010)

- Served as Lead Developer for Advanced Website pro-bono projects
- Utilized Drupal, PHP, MySQL, CMS, SEO, CSS, jQuery, HTML

#### Kitchens.com - Director of Technology (Onsite, 1999 - March 2001)

- Managed database design and maintenance
- Lead website application development

#### **Education**

#### University of Georgia

Bachelor of Business Administration degree in Management Information Systems